Muhammad Ahad Asim

Senior Software Engineer

Portfolio: https://github.com/ahad-asim/Portfolio

A Result oriented IT professional with 8 years of working experience in native mobile apps development. Developed Enterprise, VOIP, Financial, media streaming and fintech mobile application. Experience in leading teams throughout the entire software lifecycle. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of team. Experienced in client communication, requirement gathering, App design and app architecture. Ability to analyze code and engineer well-researched responsive solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Mobile Application Developer (May 2022 – August 2023)

Jingle Pay Ltd (Fintech App), Dubai, United Arab Emirates

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.jinglepay

Working as Mobile lead closely with internal teams such as developers, product, UX and QA

- Architect app using multi modular approach and applying MVVM architecture with android clean architecture.
- Main tech responsibility includes finding solution to requirements, developing new feature, reviewing code and releasing version to Google Play store.
- Constantly monitored the stability of application using various tools including crashlytics.
- Exposure to agile development process like SCRUM and expertise in JIRA and Confluence.
- Reviewed code and conduct technical interviews with questions and challenges.

Sr. Mobile Application Developer (July 2020 - April 2022)

Ebryx, Lahore, Pakistan (Kotlin, Swift)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.southeastunloading.divlog

As a senior mobile developer, I am worked here in developing android as well as IOS apps.

- Understand System and analyze complete requirements. Conduct Walk-through, requirements gathering meetings, and propose the right solution.
- Working with an international client and participating in all the scrum meetings and
- Design and architecture the apps for both platforms.
- Complete app development for both android as well as IOS by using Kotlin and swift languages.
- Client communication to deliver releases and incorporate feedback.

Sr. Android Application Developer (July 2017 - Nov 2019)

Wateen Pvt Ltd, Lahore, Pakistan (Java, Kotlin, VOIP, Web RTC)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wateen.wateenhub

Led the team and I am responsible for architecture and development for many in-house products from scratch till production.

- Estimate the finalized functional and non-functional requirements and the making of
- Design and architect modules by implementing different design patterns.
- Successfully deliver different modules and follow agile completely.
- Providing technical consultations and expertise to other teams. Also, participate in technical planning architectural exercises.



+ (971) 507300352

ahadasim07@gmail.com

Buri Residence 3, Arjan, Dubai

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahad-asim

IT Skills

Android Development **IOS** Development

Expertise

Language: Kotlin, Java, swift

Architecture:

MVVM, MVI, Modular architecture Android Clean architecture

Dependency injection: Dagger 2, Hilt, Koin

Multithreading: Coroutines

Networking: Retrofit

Unit Testing:

Junit 4, Mockito, Mockk, Espresso

CI/CD: Azure Pipelines

Version Control: SVN, GIT

SM Planning: Jira, Slack, Team

Compiler: Android studio, XCode

Tools

Android:

Jetpack component, Nav Graphs, Kotlin flows, Live Data, Rx Android Data binding, View binding, Binding adapters, Coroutines, Jetpack Compose.

Third-Party:

Firebase Crashlytics, Analytics, Remote configurations, Cloud messaging, One Signal, Sentry, App Flyer, Freshdesk, Game Changer SDK.

Payment Gateways:

Lean SDK, Mastercard payment gateway service, NGenius

Software Engineer (Dec 2016- July 2017)

Netsol Tech, Lahore, Pakistan (Android, Java)

As an android app developer my key responsibilities includes to design and develop features as per the user stories. Also responsible for releasing new builds for the team.

- Worked on developing Auto leasing and Auto financing solution for car dealers
- Release management for international clients of MBF MPOS android mobile app.
- Optimization of existing solution, Performance enhancements for different module.
- Worked on maintaining different other POS client mobile applications

Software Engineer (Feb 2015 – Nov 2016)

Ebryx Pvt Ltd, Lahore, Pakistan (Android, Java, Xamarin)

Acting as an android application developer, my core responsibilities are developing android apps from scratch and adding new features.

- Worked for local as well as international clients.
- Responsible for client communication, requirement gathering analysis, and developing the app according to the requirements.
- Optimization of existing solutions, Performance enhancements for a different module.

Active Apps

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.jinglepay

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wateen.expensemanager

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wateen.tms

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wateen.ems

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wateen.selfcare

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/seu-southeast-unloading/id1630062597

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.business.english.pod.droid

Tittes.//piay.google.com/storc/apps/uctans-iu-com.business.erigiish.pou.droid

 $\underline{\text{https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=it.neveitalia.android.ineveitalia}}$

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=uk.co.cipd.communitycatchup

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering

3.64 CGPA

International Islamic University, Islamabad, Pakistan

(2010 - 2014)

Honor/ Award Achieved

Fully funded 4-year Software Engineering Scholarship sponsored by National ICT R&D Fund Ministry of Information Technology Pakistan

Release Management

Google play console Test Flight Apple App Store Firebase App distribution Visual Studio App Center